[ Background voices ]
[背景杂音]
&gt;&gt; Good morning.
&gt;&gt; 早上好
Welcome to the understanding
欢迎来到主题为
undefined behavior session.
理解未定义行为讲解的会议
I know all of you have already
我知道大家都已经
spent countless hours debugging
在调试 Bug 上花费了无数时间
bugs that would just disappear
但当你从发布模式
when you switched from release
切换到调试模式时
to debug mode.
这些 Bug 可能就消失了
You might even have lost users
你甚至还会因为
because you couldn't reproduce
无法重现只出现在
the bugs that happened only on
用户设备上的 Bug
their device.
而丢失用户
Those might be signs that you
这些问题反映出
have undefined behavior in your
在你的代码中
code.
可能存在未定义行为
I'm Fred. I work on the client
我是 Fred
compiler team and today I'll
在客户编译器团队工作
start by explaining what
今天首先为大家讲解一下
undefined behavior is and why it
什么是未定义行为
exists.
及其存在的原因
Then we'll dive into the
然后我们会深入探讨
compiler and see how its
编译器并看看它是如何
interactions with undefined
与那些导致细微 Bug
behavior cause those subtle
的为定义行为
bugs.
相互作用的
Those bugs might not only cost
这些 Bug 不仅可能会
you a lot of debugging time.
浪费你很多的调试时间
They might have security
还可能会有一些
implications.
安全隐患
Ryan, from our security team,
来自安全团队的 Ryan
will tell you more about this
将为您讲解更多这方面的内容
and how you can use our tools to
并教您如何使用我们的工具
avoid those issues.
避免这些问题
Finally, my colleague Anna will
最后 我的同事 Anna
come to the stage and tell you
会上台讲解
how SWF tackles this problem
Swift 如何解决
space.
这些问题
So, what is undefined behavior?
那么 什么是未定义行为呢
Undefined behavior happens when
当你的代码语法正确
your code has correct syntax but
但其行为
its behavior is not within the
却超出了语言允许范围时
bounds of what the language
未定义行为就会
allows.
出现
The C and C++ standards have
C 语言和 C++ 语言
really similar definitions of
在标准上
undefined behavior in the
对未定义行为
standard.
有着非常相似的定义
Let's have a look at what the
让我们看看
C++ standard says.
C++ 语言标准是怎么定义的
Undefined behavior: Behavior for
未定义行为是指
which this international
此国际标准
standard imposes no
没有规定的
requirements.
行为
Well, that's helpful, right?
这个解释不太有用 是吧
To be fair, it comes with a note
但其实后面还跟着
that gives more details but it's
一个注解和更多细节
too long to put up on the screen
但实在太长 就没有放在屏幕上
so here's a summary.
这里是一个总结
So, what can the compiler do?
那么 编译器能够做什么呢
If you knew about undefined
如果你参加会议前就知道
behavior before coming to this
未定义行为
session, you might have heard
那么你也许听说过
that if you have undefined
如果遇到了未定义
behavior, the compiler is
行为 编译器就会
allowed to wipe your disc.
被允许抹掉你的磁盘
I guarantee this is not going to
我保证这种问题
happen.
不会出现
So, what can I do?
那我能做什么呢
The compiler can choose to
编译器可以选择
diagnose the issues using
给出警告或提示错误
warnings or errors.
来诊断问题
This is by far our preferred
这是目前为止我们
solution and it is very
最倾向于使用的解决方式
actionable on your side and it
它对开发人员来说非常可行
prevents the issue and the
可以避免问题
source.
并规避问题来源
The compiler can also choose to
编译器还可以选择
act in a documented manner.
以文本形式诊断问题
Basically, choosing to define
基本上 是选择
what the standard left
定义那些标准所未定义
undefined.
的行为
We do not do this a lot but
我们并不常用这个方法
there are some kinds of
但是有一些
undefined behavior, which are
未定义行为
way to common not to support.
是常见的不支持行为
And finally, the compiler can
最后 编译器可能会产生
produce unpredictable results.
不可预料的结果
This is the part we are going to
这会是我们今天
focus on today.
讨论的重点
Note that unpredictable includes
注意 这些不可预料的结果
is why some of those bugs will
包括你意图的行为 这就是为什么
be really evasive.
某些 Bug 很难被发现
There is a lot of undefined
在 C 族语言中
behavior in the C family of
存在大量的
languages.
未定义行为
This is just a small sample.
下面是一个简单的例子
The C standard has a list in
C 语言标准在
Annex J of all the known sources
Annex J 中有一系列未定义行为
of undefined behavior.
的已知来源
There are around 200 of them.
大概有 200 种
At this point, you might be
讲到这里 你可能会
wondering why is undefined
奇怪 为什么未定义行为
behavior even a thing?
也能成为一个问题
Why is it defined in the
为什么不能在标准中
standards?
全部定义了呢
Were people just lazy?
是因为人们很懒吗
They didn't want to define
他们不想定义
everything?
所有的行为吗
Of course, not.
当然不是
This is about tradeoffs.
这是一个折衷的选择
C has been designed to favor
C 语言的设计旨在
performance, affordability, and
提高性能 可负担性和
ease of implementation over
易于实施的
safety.
安全性
The C family of languages has
C 族语言
inherited those tradeoffs.
继承了这些折衷的选择
Those were deliberate choices
这些选择都是有意的
and they still make a lot of
并且在今天的很多情况下
sense in many circumstances
仍然起着很大
today.
的作用
Our OSs run fast thanks to them.
我们的 OS 因此运行的很快
But as with every tradeoff,
但就像每个折衷方案一样
there is a price to pay and in
总是需要付出一些代价
this case it is you, the
在这个案例中 就需要各位
developers, who are paying it.
开发人员来付出代价
This is why it is really
所以让大家
important that you know that it
了解未定义行为的存在
exists and how to deal with it.
以及如何处理是至关重要的
As I said, there are way too
就像我说的
many kinds of undefined behavior
未定义行为种类太多
to go through all of them but
没办法全部提及
let's just go through a few
但是我们可以看看
examples to make sure
一些例子 确保
everybody's on the same page.
我们达成共识
My first example is the use of
第一个例子是使用
an uninitialized value.
未初始化的值
In this function, we have a
在这个函数里 我们有一个
local variable, value.
局部变量值
It is used in the return
它在 return 语句中使用
statement but it is initialized
但只有在 if 块的条件
only if the condition to the if
为真时
block is true.
才会被初始化
If you pass any positive number
如果你将任何正数
to this function, it will invoke
传递给此函数 它将调用
undefined behavior as value will
未定义行为 因为变量值将会
be used and initialized.
被使用和初始化
In this simple case, the
在这个简单的案例中
compiler will catch the issue
编译器将捕捉到问题
and warn about it.
并发出警告
The static analyzer would give
静态分析也会提供
you that information too and it
这些信息 并且能
would catch more complex cases
发现更复杂的
of the same kind.
同类问题
My second example is about
第二个例子是
misaligned pointers.
指针偏差
In this function, we take a
在这个函数中 我们使用一个
character pointer as an argument
字符指针作为参数
but inside the function, we use
但在函数内部 我们将它
it as an integer pointer.
用作整数指针
The issue is that not every
但问题是 并非每个
character pointer is a valid
字符指针都是一个
integer pointer.
有效整数指针
Integers have to be correctly
整数必须
aligned.
正确对齐
Usually this means their address
通常这意味着 它们的地址
needs to be a multiple of four.
需要是 4 的整数倍
This kind of code will often
当在不同架构之间
cause issues when porting code
移植代码时 这种代码
between different architectures,
通常会导致问题
which have different alignment
这些架构在硬件层面上
constraints at the hardware
具有不同的
level.
对齐约束
This year, in Xcode 9 we
今年 我们在 Xcode 9 中
introduced the new Runtime tool,
引入了新的运行时工具
the Undefined Behavior
叫做“未定义行为杀毒器”
Sanitizer, which would catch
它可以
this issue.
捕捉到这个问题
My last example is about
最后一个例子是
lifetimes.
生命周期
Variables are defined only
变量仅在
within the scope -- our
作用域内定义 也就是说
variables are valued only within
我们的变量仅在其定义的
the scope they are defined in.
作用域内被赋值
Here, we take the address of the
在这里 我们使用变量
default value variable.
默认值的地址
Default is defined within the if
默认值在 if 块内定义
block and exists only there.
且只存在于该块
But by using this pointer
但是我们可以通过在块外部
outside of the block, we invoke
使用这个指针
undefined behavior.
来调用未定义行为
Again, our tools will catch
同样的 我们的工具
that.
也会捕捉到这个问题
Now that we have a better idea
对于我们正在谈论的问题
of the issues we are talking
我们现在有了更好的解决方法
about, let's take a look at how
让我们看一下
they interact with the compiler
未定义行为是如何与
and how they can produce those
编译器互相作用 以及如何
surprising bugs.
产生了那些意外的 Bug
First, let's look at what the
首先来看一下
compiler, what undefined
编译器 未定义行为
behavior means to the compiler.
对于编译器来说意味着什么
It is not actively looking for
编译器并不会主动
it to transform it in weird
寻找未定义行为 并以奇怪的
ways.
方式转化它
This is not happening.
这不会发生
But the compiler makes the
但是编译器会
assumption that there is no
假定在你的代码中
undefined behavior in your code
是没有未定义行为的
because otherwise the semantics
否则你代码的
of your code wouldn't be well
语义就不会被
defined.
很好地定义
By making this assumption, the
通过作出这一假设
compiler gathers information to
编译器会收集信息
better optimize your code.
来更好地优化你的代码
Here are a few examples.
给大家举几个例子
As it is undefined to overflow
由于未定义为溢出
assigned integer, if X is
分配的整数 如果 X
assigned integer, the compiler
被分配整数 则编译器
can assume that X is lower than
可以假设 X 低于
X + 1.
X + 1
This is a very simple but very
这是一个非常简单但
powerful assumption to make when
非常强大的假设
dealing, for example, with loop
比如说 在处理循环优化时
optimizations.
就可以作此假设
As I said, pointers need to be
就像我说过的
aligned.
指针需要对齐
And by making the assumption
通过作出假设
that they are, the compiler can
编译器可以
use more powerful memory access
使用更强大的内存访问指令
instructions like vector
如向量指令
instructions to make your code
使你的代码
way faster.
更快地运行
And last example, it is
最后一个例子是
undefined to dereference another
未定义解引用另一指针
pointer, so the compiler can
所以编译器可以
assume that each pointer that is
假设每一个被解引用的
dereferenced cannot be now and
指针都不是现在的
use this information to further
并使用这些信息来进一步
optimize your code.
优化你的代码
So, let's get a little bit more
让我们更具体一些
concrete and look at how a
看看编译器是
compiler works.
如何工作的
At a very high level, the
编译器会从很高层级
compiler takes your source code
输入你的源代码
and transforms it into an
并将其转换成
intermediate representation.
中间代码
It then applies a pipeline of
然后应用优化
optimizations to generate
流水线
optimizations to generate the
来生成
binary.
二进制文件
Each of those optimizations has
这中间的每一次优化
one goal, generate a more
都有一个目标 那就是
efficient representation of its
将输入的信息生成
input while preserving the
更有效的代码 同时
semantics.
保留语义
But I introduced the session by
但是大会开始时
talking about those bugs that
我讲了那些在
would reproduce in release mode
发布模式下会再现
but not in debug mode.
在调试模式下会消失的 Bug
So, how is that behavior
那么 这种行为
preserving?
是如何保留的呢
Let's look at a simple example.
我们来看一个简单的例子
Here we have our compiler at the
上面是我们的
top.
编译器
It has only one optimization -
它只有一种优化
dead code elimination.
死代码删除
Dead code elimination looks for
死代码删除会查找
code that cannot be executed or
无法执行的代码
that doesn't affect the result
或者对程序运行结果
of your program in any way and
没有任何影响的代码
it removes this code, thus
并将其删除 从而
making your apps smaller.
使你的 App 变得更小
Let's apply this compiler to a
让我们将这个编译器
simple function.
应用到一个简单的函数中
The function has only two
这个函数只有两个语句
statements, one variable
一个变量赋值
assignment and a return
和一个 return
statement.
语句
We run dead code elimination.
我们运行死代码删除
The variable is not used so
并没有使用变量
let's get rid of it.
让我们去掉它
And here, look at what we got.
看看这里 我们得到了什么
What happens if we pass another
如果我们将另一个指针传递给
pointer to this function?
这个函数 会发生什么情况
The unoptimized version will
未优化版本会崩溃
crash but the optimized version
而优化版本将
will happily return 42.
顺利地返回 42
So, we have a difference in
所以 它们的行为
behavior.
有差异
But by passing null to this
但是 通过传递 null 给
function, you invoked undefined
此函数 你调用了未定义行为
behavior as it is undefined to
也就是 未定义解引用
dereference another pointer.
另一个指针
I'll repeat that.
我再说一遍
It is undefined to dereference
未定义解引用
another pointer.
另一个指针
It is not defined to crash.
它没有被定义为崩溃
If dereferencing another pointer
如果解引用另一个指针
was defined to crash or if for
被定义为崩溃 或者如果
some other reason the compiler
由于某些其他原因 编译器
couldn't make the assumption
无法假定该解引用指针
that dereferenced pointers were
是有效的 那么
valid, it would be really hard
在内存访问上进行
to make any transformations on
任何转换都是
the memory accesses.
非常困难的
Like, it couldn't reorder them.
比如说 不能重新排序
It couldn't merge them or it
不能合并
couldn't remove the useless
不能删除无用的部分
ones, like we just saw.
就像我们刚才看到的那样
Dealing with memory access is a
处理内存访问是
huge part of the compiler job.
编译器工作的一个重要部分
So, here you have an example of
所以 这个例子就告诉大家
how undefined behavior changes
未定义行为是如何
the behavior of your program
在未优化代码和
between unoptimized and
优化代码间
optimized code.
改变程序行为的
But there's more I want to show
但我还想给大家
you.
展示更多的例子
Let's move to a slightly more
让我们看一个稍微
complicated example.
复杂的例子
Here again we have our compiler
我们再次把编译器
that's up and our source at the
放在上面 把源代码
bottom.
放在下面
This example is actually derived
这个例子实际上来源于
from a real issue that happened
一个真实问题
in our big open source code days
发生在几年前的
a few years ago.
开放源代码活动中
So, do not disregard it as
所以 不要把它当作
completely theoretical.
纯理论而忽略它
When you have a big function
当你有一个很大的函数
that is modified by multiple
由很多个人在很长
people over a long period of
一段时间内修改
time, it's easy to end up with
就会很容易最后变成
artifacts from the past, like
和过去一样的东西
this unused variable at the top
就像这个函数顶端没有使用过的
of the function.
变量一样
Now, let's compile this code.
现在 让我们来编译这个代码
Our new compiler has one more
我们的新编译器多了
optimization.
一种优化
Redundant null check
冗余空检查
elimination.
删除
This optimization is a
这是死代码删除
specialized version of dead code
的一个专用
elimination.
版本
It will look for pointers
它会查找与现在相比
compared against now and tries
的指针 并尝试确定
to decide if statically at this
静态时在程序的
point of the program it can
这一点 是否可以证明
prove that the pointer is either
指针是空
null or nonnull.
还是非空
And when it can do so, it just
当可以这样做时
removes the code that can never
它就会删除永远无法
be executed.
执行的代码
In this case, P is dereferenced
在这种情况下 p
in the first line of the
在函数的第一行将会被
function.
解引用
So, of course the pointer cannot
所以 指针当然
be null.
不能为空
Let's remove the null check.
让我们把空检查删掉
We then move on to our second
然后我们来看一下第二种
optimization.
优化
We already know about dead code
我们已经知道了死代码
elimination.
删除
Unused is unused.
未使用的代码未被使用
It goes away.
会被去掉
And here's the result of our
这就是我们的
compilation.
编译结果
Now, let's play the same game.
现在 让我们进行同样的操作
What happens if we pass null to
如果我们将 null 传递给
this function?
这个函数会怎么样呢
The unoptimized version will
未优化版本将
crash.
崩溃
The optimized version will crash
优化后的版本
too.
也会崩溃
But note that they don't crash
但请注意 它们崩溃的地方
in the same spot.
是不同的
The unoptimized version crashes
未优化版本会在
on the first line.
第一行上崩溃
The optimized version crashes on
优化后的版本在
the last line.
最后一行上崩溃
Those could be hundreds of
这中间可能差了
thousands of lines away.
成千上万行
This is a very important lesson
这对于了解
to learn about undefined
未定义行为
behavior.
是非常重要的
When it causes an issue, whether
当未定义行为引起问题时
it is another reference, an
无论是另一个引用
integer overflow, memory
整数溢出
corruption due to an out of
由于超出限制访问的
bound access or any other kind
内存损坏 或任何
of undefined behavior, the
其他类型的未定义行为
symptom you see will often be
你看到的症状通常
very far away from the root
与问题的根本原因
cause of the issue.
相差甚远
There is one more thing I want
还有一件事我想
to show you.
展示给大家看
Let's restart the compilation
我们用一个稍微
with a slightly different
不同的编译器
compiler.
重新启动编译
As you see, we just see swapped
如你所见 我们只是
the two optimizations.
交换了两种优化
Let's compile the same code
我们再次编译相同
again.
的代码
Dead code elimination, unused is
死代码删除 未使用的代码
still unused.
仍未使用
It goes away.
它消失了
Now we try to apply redundant
现在我们尝试应用
null check elimination.
冗余空检查删除
There is nothing to - there is
对于 p 指针的值
nothing to reason anymore about
没有任何理由进行处理
the value of the P pointer so
所以优化
the optimization just does
并没有什么
nothing.
作用
And here's the result of our
这是我们第二次编译
second compilation of the same
相同代码的
code.
结果
Note that in this case if you
请注意 在这种情况下
pass a null pointer to the
如果将空指针传递到
optimized version, it will not
优化后的版本 则不会
crash.
崩溃
Now, imagine your app has the
现在 假设你的 App
code on the left and the
代码在左边
developer who added the null
开发人员在这个函数中的某个点
check to this function at some
添加了一个空的检查功能
point added a few uses of the
并添加了另一个
function with another argument.
函数的参数的一些使用
You might have never realized
你可能从来没有意识到
that it is an issue because your
这是一个问题
compiler is acting like compiler
因为你的编译器就像编译器 2
2.
一样
But there is no guarantee that
但是不能保证在将来
in the future it will not act
它不会出现像编译器 1 中
like compiler 1 and break your
那样的行为 并破坏你的
code.
代码
This is maybe the most important
这可能是关于未定义行为
thing to remember about
需要记住的
undefined behavior.
最重要的事情
The fact that you don't have an
你今天没有问题
issue today doesn't mean that
并不意味着编译器中的
that change in the compiler will
这种变化不会
not cause it to break in the
导致它在
future.
将来崩溃
And your compiler might be
你的编译器可能
changing behavior more than you
会比你想象中的
think.
更多变
During a single day, each time
在一天之内 每次
you switch between debug and
你在调试和发布模式之间
release mode or each time you
切换时 或者每次
change the optimization
更改优化设置时
settings, you run a different
都会运行不同的
instance of the compiler with a
编译器实例 并将一组
very different set of
非常不同的转换
transformations applied to your
应用到你的
code.
代码中
Maybe more surprisingly, each
也许更令人惊讶的是
time you switch from a real
每次你从真实设备
device to a simulator or vice
切换到模拟器 或者反过来
versa, you are targeting a
你都会定向至
different architecture, which
不同的架构
might react differently to
这可能会对未定义行为
undefined behavior.
产生不同的反应
And, of course, each time you
当然 每次
upgrade Xcode to a new major
将 Xcode 升级到一个新的
version, you get a brand new
主要版本时 你都会得到一个
compiler.
全新的编译器
And we work hard all year long
而且我们一直在努力
to make the compiler better,
使编译器生成更好
generate faster, smaller code.
更快和更小的代码
Many of those improvements could
许多这些改进
reveal undefined behavior in
都可能在你的代码中引发
your code.
未定义行为
So, before moving along, just,
在继续之前
let's just summarize what we
让我来总结一下我们
learned about undefined
了解到了哪些关于未定义行为的
behavior.
信息
Undefined behavior will not
未定义行为不会
trigger bugs reliably.
总是触发 Bug
One of your configurations could
可能你的一个配置
be working while the other one
正在工作时 另一个就
breaks.
中断了
When undefined behavior breaks,
当未定义行为出现
when it breaks your code, the
并中断代码时
symptom you are seeing might be
你所看到的症状可能
thousands of lines away or maybe
距离问题的根本原因
even hours of executions away
有数千行之远
from the real root cause of the
或者甚至间隔了几个小时的执行
issue.
时间
This could be really hard to
如果你没有
debug if you are not prepared
做好准备的话
for it.
这可能真的很难调试
And lastly, the fact that you
最后一点是
don't have any bugs today that
你今天没有任何
you know of doesn't mean that
已知晓的错误，并不意味着
you don't have any bugs due to
你不会遇到任何由未定义行为
undefined behavior.
引起的错误
And if you have undefined
如果存在未定义行为
behavior, it will break at some
就会在将来的
point in the future.
某个时间引发中断
When it breaks, it could cost
当它引发中断时 可能会
you a lot of debugging time but
花费你很多的调试时间
it could also put your users'
但也可能会使你的用户数据处于危险之中
data at risk.
处于危险之中
Here's Ryan to tell you more
这是Ryan 他会为你讲解更多的
about the security implications
关于未定义行为的
of undefined behavior.
安全隐患
[ Applause ]
[掌声]
&gt;&gt; Thanks, Fred.
&gt;&gt; 谢谢 Fred
So, who here remembers the
那么 大家有谁还记得
heartbleed vulnerability from a
几年前的“心脏出血“
few years ago?
安全漏洞吗
Well, if you're like me, you
如果你像我一样
probably had to go and change
可能不得不会去
your password on like 100
100 个不同的网站
different websites or maybe
修改密码 或者也许
patch some of your own backend
为你自己的后台服务器
servers.
打补丁
Well, heartbleed was an
“心脏出血”是一种
out-of-bounds read in a widely
在广泛使用的
used cryptographic library
OpenSSL 的密码库中的
called open SSL.
越界读取
By sending just one packet to an
通过向受影响的服务器
affected server, an attacker
发送一个数据包 攻击者
would receive in reply a few
就会收到服务器
kilobytes of the server
进程堆内存的
process's heap memory, which
几千字节 这引发了
turned into a pretty significant
相当严重的隐私泄漏
privacy and security exposure.
和安全问题
Now, that out-of-bounds read in
“心脏出血”的越界读取
heartbleed is an example of
就是一个未定义行为
undefined behavior and it turns
的例子 而事实证明
out that undefined behavior is
未定义行为是
at the core of many different
许多不同类型的
types of security
安全漏洞的
vulnerabilities.
核心
To name just a few, you could
仅举几个例子 你就可以
think of buffer overflows, uses
想到缓冲区溢出
of uninitialized variables, heat
未初始化变量的使用
misuse bugs like use after free
和 Heat Misuse Bug
and double free.
比如 Use-After-Free 和 Double Free
And also race conditions.
还有竞争条件漏洞
So, keep in mind that your users
所以 请记住 你的用户
trust your app and potentially
信任你的 App  并且可能会
with their personal information
留有他们的个人信息
such as their photos or their
比如照片或
private messages.
私人信息
And so you should do everything
所以你应该尽一切可能
you can to make sure that your
来确保你的 App
app is as safe and secure as
的安全
possible.
和可靠
And if you're a framework
如果你是框架
developer, remember that your
开发人员 就需要记住
client apps inherit all of your
你的 App 客户端
bugs, just like all those
会继承所有 Bug
websites inherited the
就像所有这些网站都继承了
heartbleed vulnerability.
“心脏出血”漏洞一样
But the good news that there are
但好消息是
tools that could help you.
有些工具可以帮助你
Now, too often we developers
目前 开发人员往往
reach for our tools only after a
只有在 Bug 以某些方式显现的
bug has manifested some other
情况下才会使用
way.
我们的工具
Maybe it showed up in our users'
比如 Bug 出现在了用户的
crash logs.
崩溃日志中
But by running tools early and
但如果在早期以及
often throughout development, we
整个开发过程中就运行工具
can catch these issues before
我们就可以在它们
they ever become a problem that
发展成问题并影响用户之前
affects our customers.
就捕捉到这些问题
So, I wanted to relate a story
我想举一个例子
of how one of these tools,
告诉你们 作为这些工具之一的
Address Sanitizer, saved macOS
“地址杀毒器”是如何拯救
Yosemite.
macOS Yosemite 的
So, about one month before the
在 macOS Yosemite
macOS Yosemite public release,
公开发布前一个月左右
many new crashes started
许多新的崩溃开始
appearing throughout the system.
出现在整个系统中
And we had a hunch that we had a
我们预感在一个
heap corruption bug that was in
低层系统框架中
one of the low-level system
存在一个堆腐败
frameworks.
Bug
Well, we were having a really
我们当时费了很大力气
hard time reproducing the issue.
重现这个问题
And without being able to
但并没有成功
reproduce it, we didn't have a
也没有确切的证据
smoking gun that was pointing to
能够指出一个
a specific function that was
特定的函数导致了
causing the heap corruption.
堆腐败
And so we turned to a tool that
所以我们转而使用
at the time was very new, called
一种名为“地址杀毒器”的工具
Address Sanitizer, and we
这在当时是非常新的工具
thought it would help us catch
我们认为它可以捕捉到
this heap corruption bug.
这个堆腐败错误
So, we instrumented some of the
所以 我们测试了一些
system frameworks and we loaded
系统框架 并加载了
it up.
这个工具
And sure enough, Address
当然 “地址杀毒器”
Sanitizer did its job
完美地解决了
wonderfully and honed right in
问题 锁定了
on this piece of code.
这片代码
So, to summarize it briefly, we
总结一下就是
had a CF string and we were
我们有一个 CF 字符串
constructing a path to a file
并正在构建用户库
inside the user's library
缓存目录中的一个
cache's directory.
文件路径
And then we needed to convert
然后我们将这个 C 字符串
this C string, sorry, convert
抱歉 将这个 CF 字符串
this CF string into a C string.
转换成一个 C 字符串
And so, I mean, that's a pretty
所以 我的意思是说 这是
straightforward thing, right?
一个非常简单的事情 对吧
We have to measure the length of
我们必须测量 CF 字符串
the CF string, allocate buffer
的长度 然后再将缓冲区
on the heap of that many
分配到这个有许多
characters and copy the bytes
字符的堆上 并将字节
into it.
拷贝进去
And, oh yeah.
而且 对了
We forgot one thing which is
我们忘了一件事 就是
that C strings need to be null
C 字符串需要被
terminated.
空终止
And so we have to add that too.
所以我们也要补充这一点
But we made a mistake, an off by
但是我们犯了一个错误
one error.
“大小差一”错误
Because we didn't include that
因为当我们计算
null byte when we were computing
所需分配大小时
the size of the allocation that
没有包含这个
we needed.
空字节
And so we actually overflowed
所以实际上我们
our buffer.
溢出了缓冲区
But most of the time this didn't
但大部分情况下这对
have any impact on the user.
用户没有任何影响
And that's because the heap will
那是因为堆会
round up the size of the
扩大分配
allocation.
尺寸
In this case, let's say we
在这种情况下 假设我们
rounded it up to the next
将其向上舍入到
multiple of 16 bytes.
16 个字节的下一个倍数
And so when we write our null
然后 当我们最后将
byte into that unused space at
空字节写入未使用
the end, that there's no
空间时 就不会有
consequence, right?
任何后果了 对吧
But let's see what happens when
但是让我们看看
one of the variables in that
当缓冲区中的一个变量
buffer changes, and that's the
发生变化时会发生什么
username.
那就是用户名
Well, if the length of the
如果用户名的长度
username changes, the amount of
改变了 未使用的
unused space would also change.
空间量也会改变
And it turned out that if the
而事实证明
user's username was exactly 11
如果用户的用户名长度正好是
characters long, there wouldn't
11个字符 则不会有
be any unused space and we would
任何未使用的空间，那我们最终
end up corrupting the adjacent
会破坏堆上的
object on the heap and causing
相邻对象 导致
some other part of the code to
代码的其他部分
crash.
崩溃
And so this was the secret to
所以这就是为什么
why it was so hard to catch
用正常方法捕捉
normally but Address Sanitizer
不到问题 但是“地址杀毒器”
did a great job of finding it
却能够马上
right away.
找到它
Now, in this case, this off by
在这种情况下 这个
one probably didn't have many
缓冲溢出错误可能没有
security consequences.
导致很多安全性后果
But many other similar bugs can
但许多其他类似的 Bug
result in exploitable
可能会导致可利用的
vulnerabilities.
漏洞
And remember that security flaws
请记住 安全漏洞
often don't manifest until
通常只有在被利用的时候
they've been exploited.
才会显现出来
So, running tools like Address
因此 在早期和整个开发过程中
Sanitizer early and throughout
运行的类似于“地址杀毒器”
the development process can help
的工具 可以帮助你
you catch these before they ever
在这些错误到达
reach your customer devices.
客户设备之前将其捕捉
So, let's talk about the tools
那么 让我们来谈谈
that you have at your disposal
你所掌握的用来捕捉
to catch undefined behavior.
未定义行为的工具
First we'll talk about the
首先 我们将讨论编译器
compiler, the static analyzer in
Xcode 中的静态分析器
Xcode, and the Sanitizers -
以及杀毒器
Address Sanitizer, Thread
“地址杀毒器”“线程杀毒器”
Sanitizer and the Undefined
和“未定义行为
Behavior Sanitizer.
杀毒器”
So, let's start with the
我们先从编译器
compiler.
开始
So, the compiler alerts you to
编译器会提醒你
parts of your code that might be
部分代码可能有些可疑
a little suspicious and it does
并以编译器警告
this in the form of compiler
的形式
warnings.
提醒你
Believe it or not, they're not
信不信由你
just there to annoy you.
它们不只是在烦你
Now, every release of Xcode has
Xcode 的每个版本都有
better warnings and great
更好的警告功能和
features like fixits, so you can
很好的功能 比如 Fixit
resolve them with just one
所以你只需点按一下
click.
即可解决问题
To learn what's new in the
如果想要了解今年
compiler this year, check out
编译器的新功能
the What's New in LLDM talk
你可以听一下今天下午关于 LLDM
which is later this afternoon.
新功能的演讲
Now, you might be wondering, do
现在 你可能会想
I have the recommended set of
我的项目是否已经
warnings turned on for my
启用了一组推荐的
project?
警告呢
Well, every time you upgrade
其实 每次你升级 Xcode 时
Xcode, you'll be presented with
都有机会使你的项目
the opportunity to modernize
更加的
your project.
先进
And you can also do this at any
你也可以随时使用
time using the validate settings
验证设置选项
option and that'll help you get
进行此操作 这将有助于
into a good state again.
系统再次处于良好状态
And there's one more build
还有一个我认为
setting that I think you should
你应该了解的
know about which is treat
构建设置是
warnings as errors.
将警告视为错误
And it does what it says on the
它会像它名字所说的那样
tin.
行动
If your project already compiles
如果你的项目已经编译了
with relatively few warnings,
相对较少的警告
consider turning that on and
那么请考虑开启
enforcing the self-discipline to
这个设置 并强化它的自律
keep that compiler count low.
以保持较低的最大并行编译数
Now, let's talk about the static
现在 我们来谈谈
analyzer.
静态分析仪
The static analyzer can be
你可以将静态分析仪
thought of as a supercharged
看作是编译器警告的
version of compiler warnings.
加强版本
It explores your code and finds
它会探索你的代码
bugs that only happen in very
并发现只有在非常特殊的
particular conditions, maybe
条件下才会出现的 Bug
conditions that aren't being hit
可能在你通常测试
when you normally test your app.
应用程序时都不会遇到的条件
So, what we recommend doing is
所以我们建议在每次
analyzing during every build.
编译的过程中进行分析
There's a build setting for this
它有一个专门的构建设置
and when you turn it on, Xcode
开启后 在你每次构建
will run a fast analysis pass
项目时  Xcode 都将运行
every time you build your
一个快速的
project.
分析传递
And that makes sure that you can
这可以确保你能
find bugs that you've just
尽快找到
introduced as quickly as
刚刚引入的
possible.
Bug
But there's also a deeper mode
但是分析仪还有一个
that the analyzer can run in and
更深的模式 可以
you can use that at any time,
随时使用
and that's the mode that we
也是我们建议
recommend using under your
在持续集成下
continuous integration in order
使用的模式 从而
to make the most of the static
充分利用
analyzer's bug finding
静态分析仪的
capabilities.
错误查找功能
So, next I'm going to talk about
接下来我要谈谈
the Sanitizers.
杀毒器
But first to note, the
但首先要注意的是
Sanitizers are Runtime tools.
杀毒器是运行时工具
Unlike the compiler or the
与编译器或静态分析仪不同
static analyzer, to get the most
为了充分利用
out of the Sanitizers, you need
杀毒器 你需要
to actually run an exerciser
实际运行一个
code that can only find bugs in
只能在实际执行的代码中
code that's actually being
找到 Bug 的
executed.
练习代码
So, keep that in mind.
请记住这一点
But they offer a high degree of
它们提供了高度的
bug finding capabilities.
错误查找能力
So, first as I mentioned before,
首先 如前所述
there's Address Sanitizer.
我们有“地址杀毒器”
Now, Address Sanitizer catches
现在 “地址杀毒器”可以捕获
memory corruption bugs like
诸如缓冲区溢出
buffer overflows and
和 Use-After-Free
use-after-free bugs.
之类的内存损坏 Bug
And these ones are highly
而这些与
correlated with security
安全漏洞
vulnerabilities.
高度相关
Then there's Thread Sanitizer,
然后是“线程消毒器”
which catches data races.
它可以捕获数据竞争
So, in your multithreaded app,
因此 在你的多线程 App 中
if two threads tried to access
如果两个线程尝试访问
the same piece of memory without
同一片内存 而没有
proper synchronization, you have
进行正确的同步 则会发生
a data race.
数据竞争
But a cool thing about Thread
但是 “线程消毒器”的一个
Sanitizer is that it catches
好酷地方是 它甚至可以
even potential data races.
捕捉到潜在的数据竞争
So, even if in your execution of
所以 即使在执行
the app everything seems to be
App 时一切看起来似乎
working great, Thread Sanitizer
都很好的情况下“线程消毒器”
can tell you if two operations
都可能会告诉你 两个操作
could potentially happen in a
是否有可能会
different order and cause your
以不同的顺序发生 并导致
app to misbehave.
你的 App 行为不当
And new in Xcode 9 is the
Xcode 9 中新增的是
Undefined Behavior Sanitizer.
“未定义行为杀毒器”
It catches over 15 different
它可以捕获超过 15 种
types of undefined behavior and
不同类型的未定义行为
it extends either Address
扩展了“地址杀毒器”
Sanitizer or Thread Sanitizer so
或“线程杀毒器”的功能
you get even more bug-finding
以便你获得强的 Bug
power.
查找能力
So, some of these types of
因此 它捕获的一些这些类型的
undefined behavior that it
未定义行为包括
catches include assigned integer
分配整数溢出和
overflows and tightness match
紧密匹配 Bug
bugs, which are also somewhat
这也与某些
related to security
环境下的
vulnerabilities in some
安全漏洞
contexts.
有关
All of the sanitizers provide
所有的杀毒器
you with really rich and
都为你提供了丰富而且
informative diagnostics that
富含信息的诊断程序
help you hone in on the root
帮助你锁定 Bug 出现的
cause of a bug.
根本原因
You can find a lot of really
你可以在“运行时问题
helpful information in the
导航器”中找到很多
Runtime Issue Navigator such as
非常有用的信息
stack backtraces at important
例如在 Bug 执行期间
parts during the bug's
重要部分的
execution.
堆栈回溯信息
So, we recommend turning on the
所以 我们建议在开发过程中
sanitizers during development.
启动杀毒器
You can do this in the scheme
你可以在诊断选项卡下的
editor under the diagnostics
Scheme 编辑器中
tab.
执行此操作
And this is where you can also
你也可以在这里
turn it on for running your unit
将它启动 来运行你的
tests.
单元测试
And remember that the sanitizers
记住 杀毒器需要
need good code coverage in order
良好的代码覆盖 以便
to find bugs throughout your
在整个程序中
program, and that's something
查找 Bug  这是
that your unit test can provide.
你的单元测试可以提供的
You can learn more about the
你可以在“使用 Xcode 运行时工具
sanitizers and other Runtime
查找错误”讲座中
tools that are new this year in
了解更多关于 Xcode
Xcode at the Finding Bugs Using
今年新的杀毒器和
Xcode Runtime Tools talk.
其他的运行时工具
So, those are five powerful
所以 这些是你可以用来
tools that you have at your
追踪未定义行为的
disposal to track down undefined
五个强大工具 还可以
behavior and address some of the
用来解决未定义行为
security vulnerabilities that
可能产生的一些
they may create.
安全漏洞
But before moving on, there's
但在继续之前
one more thing that I wanted to
还有一件事我想
talk about, which is the
谈一下 那就是
language itself.
语言本身
So, you can think of your use of
你可以将语言的
the language as your first line
使用作为编写
of defense in writing safe and
安全可靠代码的
secure code.
第一道防线
And so with that in mind, you
考虑到这一点
should prefer the safe
你应该更注重
constructs that your library and
库和语言为你提供的
your language provide to you.
安全结构
For instance, automatic
例如  Objective C 中的
reference counting in Objective
自动引用
C.
计数
Or smart pointers in C++ free
或者 C++ 中的智能指针
you from the burden of having to
可以将你从繁重的手动内存
do a lot of the manual memory
管理中解脱出来
management that results in bugs.
从而避免 Bug
And if your standard library
如果你的标准库
provides you with container
为你提供容器类
classes like NSarray from
例如基础的 NSarray
foundation, which check their
它们会自动
bounds automatically, you don't
检查其边界 则不必
have to worry so much about
太过担心
buffer overflows.
缓冲区溢出
But it's just key to understand
但是 了解你的语言
the tradeoffs that your language
在安全和保障方面
is making when it comes to
所做的折衷
safety and security.
才是关键所在
And when these are very
当在你的代码中这些是
important factors in your code,
非常重要的因素时
consider using SWF, a language
请考虑使用 Swift
that was designed from the
这种语言从最开始
ground up to eliminate entire
设计时就消除了
categories of undefined
所有类别的
behavior.
未定义行为
And to tell you more about that,
为了向你们介绍更多相关内容
I'd like to invite up my
我想邀请我的
colleague, Anna.
同事 Anna 来为大家继续讲解
[ Applause ]
[掌声]
&gt;&gt; Thank you, Ryan.
&gt;&gt; 谢谢你 Ryan
Now let's talk about undefined
现在让我们来谈谈
behavior and SWF.
未定义行为和 Swift
While you can write code
你可以在 Swift 中
fine-tuned for performance in
编写适合性能的代码
SWF, this language makes
这种语言会
different tradeoffs and was
进行不同的权衡
designed to be much safer by
同时它被设计在默认的情况下
default.
更加安全
As you've seen from the previous
从前面的例子可以看出
examples, undefined behavior can
未定义行为可以
introduce very subtle bugs that
引入非常微妙的错误
in turn could lead to security
从而导致
exploits.
安全漏洞
And this is simply summarized in
这在来自 Swift.org 的这段代码中
this code from SWF.org.
进行了简单总结
Undefined behavior is the enemy
未定义行为是
of safety.
安全的敌人
Safety in SWF is important on
Swift 的安全性
many levels.
在很多层面都很重要
Let's see how some of the major
让我们看看针对 Ryan
sources of undefined behavior
和 Fred 谈到的一些
that Ryan and Fred talked about
未定义行为的主要来源
are addressed in SWF using
如何使用 Swift 中的
different techniques.
不同技术进行解决
The stricter type system gives
更严格的类型系统给了
us optional types, which
我们可选的类型
statically prevent null point of
这静态地预防了解引用
dereferences.
空点
Use of an initialized variables
初始化变量的使用
is eliminated by guarantee of
通过明确的初始化
definite initialization.
被消除了
Buffer and integer overflows are
缓冲区和整数溢出
checked at runtime and just like
将会在运行时被检查 就像
in Objective C, automatic
Objective C  一样
reference counting is the SWF
自动引用计数
answer to use after freeze as it
是冻结后  Swift 作出的响应
allows the developer not to
它允许开发人员
focus on manual memory
不专注于手动管理
management issues.
内存的问题
So, let's look into some of this
让我们更详细地
in more detail.
研究一下
Optional types is SWF answer to
可选类型是 Swift
null point of dereferences.
对解引用空点的响应
SWF has two kinds of types.
Swift 有两种类型
Here we have a nonoptional cake
这里 我们有一个不可选的蛋糕
and an optional cake, which you
和一个可选的蛋糕 你可以
can think of as a box that may
认为后者中有蛋糕
have a cake in it or might be
或认为它只是一个空
empty.
盒子
Now, as SWF tools, I can assure
现在 作为 Swift 工具
you a bug that may have a cake
我可以向你保证 不确定盒子中是否有蛋糕
in it is definitely not the same
这样的 Bug 绝对不会像
thing as this delicious triple
这个美味的三层巧克力蛋糕
chocolate delight.
一样令人愉悦
So, before using a value of
所以 在使用可选类型的值
optional type, you need to check
之前 须先进行
for it.
检查
Suppose we have a function
假设我们有一个函数叫做
called receive package that is
接收包 声明将返回
declared to return an optional
一个可选的
cake type.
蛋糕类型
Don't jump for joy unless you
不要高兴的太早
check and know for sure that it
除非你已经检查并确定
will not return nil.
它不会返回为 nil
It's possible the cake is a lie.
有可能蛋糕是个谎言
Note that SWF's syntax provides
请注意  Swift 的语法提供了
affordances for easy checking of
可以轻松检查可选类型
optional types, specifically to
的功能 特别是能
lessen the burden of using this
减轻开发人员
types on the developer.
使用此类型的负担
Another important reminder is
另一个重要的提醒是
that you should not abuse the
你不应该滥用第四个
fourth unwrap operator, which
解包操作符
will stop execution of the
对于这种操作符 如果值为 nil
program if the value is nil.
则会停止该程序的执行
If the API has been declared to
如果 API 已经声明
return an optional, it means
将返回一个可选类型
that it might return nil so
就意味着它可能返回 nil
check for it.
所以要先进行检查
Now, the fourth unwrap should
第四个解包操作符
only be used in rare cases when
只能在极少数情况下使用
you, the developer, know for
就是当开发人员确定
sure and can guarantee that the
并且可以保证返回值
return value is never nil.
永远不会为 nil 的时候
However, that cannot be encoded
然而 它不能在
in the type system.
类型系统中被编码
One example of that is when
举个例子 当你从
you're loading an image asset
App 数据包中
from the app bundle.
加载图像资源时
SWF also has a notion of
Swift 还有一个
implicitly unwrapped optional
隐含解开的可选类型的
type.
概念
This type is similar to
此类型与可选类型
optional.
类似
However, here the compiler does
然而 在这里编译器并不强制
not enforce that the values are
使用这些值
used before, the values are
在使用之前会
checked before use, making no
先检查这些值
compile time guarantees.
不保证编译时间
However, note that this type is
请注意 这种类型
still much safer than the C
仍然比 C 指针类型
pointer type because using it is
安全得多 因为使用它的是
defined behavior.
已定义行为
If the value's nil, the program
如果值为 nil  那么程序就会
is guaranteed to stop execution,
停止执行
making this model much more
这使得该模型更加
secure.
安全
Now, this type should be used
现在 此类型应该在
for properties that are
确定有值的属性中
guaranteed to have a value.
使用
However, they cannot be
然而 它们不能在
initialized in the constructor.
构造函数中被初始化
Some of you might be using it
你们中的一些人可能会把它用于
for IB outlets.
IB 输出口
However, another source of
然而 隐含解开的可选类型
implicitly unwrapped optionals
的另一个来源是
are pointered types coming from
来自 Objective C 和
Objective C and C APIs.
C 的 API 的指针类型
And this source subverts the
这个来源颠覆了
type safety of SWF optionals.
Swift 可选类型的类型安全性
So, what can we do here?
那我们能做什么呢
At the time SWF was released,
在 Swift 发布的时候
we've also added nullability
我们还向 Apple LLDM
annotations to the Apple LLDM
编译器添加了
compiler.
可空性注解
This annotation in C languages
在 C 语言中
communicate the intent of the
这个注释传达了
APIs but are also used to
API 的意图 但也用于
enhance their SWF interfaces.
增强 Swift 的接口
They allow us to map the unsafe
它们允许我们将不安全的
C pointers onto the optional
C 指针映射到可选
types.
类型
Let's look at this example.
我们来看这个例子
Here we have ancestor shared
我们在 NSview 中
with view method on NSview.
有一个 ancestorSharedWithView 方法
As you can see here, it takes a
如你所见 它需要一个
non-null argument because it
非空的参数 因为
does not make sense to look for
在 nil 和某个值之间
an ancestor between a nil and a
寻找祖先是没有
value.
意义的
On the other hand, its return
另一方面 它的
value is nullable because it's
返回值为空 因为
possible the two views do not
两个视图可能没有
have the same ancestor.
相同的祖先
Now, as you can see here,
现在 你可以在这里看到
nullability directly maps onto
可空性直接映射到
the SWF interface.
Swift 界面
Non-null maps into the
非空映射到
nonoptional value and nullable
非可选值 可空
is mapped to the optional value.
映射到可选值
Good news is that most Apple
好消息是 大多数
APIs have been audited and
Apple API 已经通过
annotated with nullability
可空性注解进行了
annotations.
审核和注释
However, if you have APIs or
但是 如果你有 API 或
just C or Objective C code that
只是 C 或 Objective C 代码
interoperates with SWF, you too
与 Swift 进行互操作 你也可以
can benefit from these
从这些注解中
annotations.
受益
In addition, you can use tools
此外 你可以使用
such as the [inaudible] Static
静态分析器
Analyzer, Warnings, and
警告和
Undefined Behavior Sanitizer to
“未定义行为消毒器”等工具
find inconsistencies of how this
来找到在你的 C
these annotations are applied on
或 Objective C 代码中的
your C code or Objective C code.
注解方式不一致的地方
Now, I really, really like this
我真的非常喜欢下面这个
example because it highlights
例子 因为它突出
how the improvements to the LLDM
了 LLDM 编译器，
compiler, the SWF compiler, and
Swift 编译器和
the frameworks work all together
框架三者如何一起合作的改进
to benefit the whole ecosystem.
进一步使整个生态系统受益
SWF definite initialization is a
Swift 明确初始化是基于
diagnostic feature based on deep
深层代码分析的
code analysis.
诊断功能
The SWF compiler guarantees that
Swift 的编译器保证
values are initialized before
使用值之前
they are being used.
将它们初始化
And this checking is done along
这个检查是通过
all branches through your
你整个程序的所有分支
program.
完成的
Let's look at this example.
我们来看一下这个例子
Here, the compiler will check
在这里 编译器将会检查
that my instance is initialized
我的实例是否在
on both the if and the else
此代码段的 if 和 else
branch of this code snippet
分支上初始化
before it allows you to go on
然后才允许你继续
and use this value.
使用此值
Now, let's talk about buffer and
现在 我们来谈谈缓冲区和
integer overflows, which are the
整数溢出 这是
biggest sources of security
安全问题的最大
issues.
来源
Overflows only raise an integer
溢出只需要增加一个整数
and SWF terminate the execution
Swift 就会终止
of the program.
程序的执行
You might ask this question.
你可能会问
Why is Runtime checking good?
为什么运行时检查没有问题呢
Well, while your program will
如果出现 Bug 且
still stop if you have a bug and
你的缓冲区溢出了
your buffer overflows, this
尽管你的程序会停止运行时检查也会好于
behavior is much better than the
运行时检查也会好于
alternative.
它
The behavior in SWF is much more
Swift 中的行为
consistent and debuggable than
比 C 中的更加
what you get in C and most
一致并具有更高的可调试性
importantly, it gives very high
最重要的是它提供了非常高的
security guarantees.
安全性保证
The buffer overflow is not
缓冲区溢出是不可
exploitable.
利用的
It will not lead to the attacker
它不会导致攻击者
getting execution control of
获得你的程序的
your program.
执行控制能力
Note that if you need to use
注意 如果你需要用到
integer-wrapping behavior, you
整数包装行为
can still do it using overflow
仍然可以使用
operators, which are also safe
溢出操作符 这也是安全的
and just perform modular
而且只是执行
arithmetic.
模数运算
Now, a question a lot of you
现在 大家
might be thinking about now is
可能想到的一个问题是
does undefined behavior exist in
Swift 中存在
SWF?
未定义行为吗
And the answer is yes, but this
答案是肯定的 但是这种
case is much rarer and often we
情况是非常罕见的 并且通常情况下我们
know that we are opting into
知道自己在选择不安全的
unsafe behavior.
行为
So, for example we needed C
例如我们需要 C 的
interoperability.
互操作性
So, we needed to traffic in
我们需要与这些类型进行
these types.
数据通信
Unsafe pointer, unsafe mutable
不安全的指针 不安全的
raw buffer pointer.
可变原始缓冲指针
Note that you can tell that
注意 你可以仅仅通过查看
these types are unsafe by just
它们的名字就知道
looking at their names.
它们是不安全的
So, if your applications use C
所以 如果你的应用程序使用 C
or Objective C or otherwise
或 Objective C
they're using these types, I
其他用到这些类型的方式
highly recommend using Address
我强烈推荐使用
Sanitizer too.
“地址杀毒器”
It will find memory corruptions
它会发现这种不安全
that this unsafety could bring
可能会给你的代码带来的
to your code.
内存损坏
Now, another example of unsafety
现在  另一个 Swift
in SWF are simultaneous
不安全的例子是
accesses.
同时访问
And SWF is nailing the model
Swift 正在通过强制执行
down in this release with
独占内存访问
enforcement of exclusive memory
将这个典型固定在
access.
本版本中
Let's look at a very simple
为了更清楚地理解
example to understand what this
让我们来看一个非常简单的
is all about.
例子
So, here we have a function that
在这里我们有一个函数
takes two in out arguments.
含有两个 inout 参数
In out means that the function
inout 表示该函数
may change the value of these
可能会更改这些
arguments.
参数的值
Calling this function and
调用此函数并
passing it two values that point
将两个指向相同内存的值
to the same memory could result
传递给它 可能会导致
in unpredictable behavior.
不可预测的行为
For those of you who are
对于你们当中
familiar with restrictive work
熟悉 C 中的 restrict 的人
in C, this is very similar.
这是非常相似的
But in SWF, this behavior is on
但是在 Swift 中 此行为
by default.
是默认开启的
Now, this one, this is a very
接下来是一个关于这个问题的
simple and abstract example of
非常简单抽象
this problem.
的例子
However, I highly encourage you
我非常推荐大家
to watch Watch New in SWF talk
去看“Swift 新特性”讲座
for more examples of how this
以获得更多的例子
could be visible in your code
了解在代码中这些问题是如何可见的
and how it relates to your code.
以及它们与代码的关联
So, to address this problem, SWF
为了解决这个问题 Swift
could have chose to declare this
可以选择将其声明为
to be undefined behavior.
未定义行为
However, instead it decided to
然而 Swift 并
follow its mantra, that
没有改变 因为
undefined behavior is the enemy
未定义行为是
of safety and implement
语言中安全性和可实施解决方案
solutions in the language that
这些提供强有力保障手段
provide stronger guarantees.
的一个敌人
Coming up with the right
在这里 找到正确的
solution here is a balancing
解决方案是一种
act.
平衡的举动
It's best to diagnose everything
最好是静态地诊断一切
statically but often that's not
但是通常情况下
possible without making the type
都会造成
system too difficult to use.
类型系统很难使用
Another solution are Runtime
另一个解决方案是运行时
checks.
检查
However, the language Runtime
然而 语言运行时
has to be performant.
必须是高性能
And efficient.
且高效的
And the overhead of any extra
任何额外检查的系统
checking cannot be too high.
都不能占用过高的系统资源
So, the solution that the SWF
因此 Swift 项目提出的
Project came up with consists of
解决方案包括
tightening the language to
紧实语言
follow a slightly stricter rule
遵循更严格的规则
and using a combination of
以及结合使用
static and dynamic checks to
静态和动态检查
ensure that unintended sharing
确保在同一个
does not happen within the same
线程中不会发生
thread.
意外共享
Unfortunately, checking for
遗憾的是
exclusivity of accesses across
在线程之间检查访问独占性
threads is too expensive.
成本太高
And the tradeoff that was made
这里所做的折衷
here was to rely on tools,
是依靠工具
specifically Thread Sanitizer,
特别是“线程杀毒器”
to catch violations involving
以捕捉涉及
accesses from multiple threads.
多线程访问的违规行为
In general, using Thread
一般来说 使用“线程消毒器”
Sanitizer is very beneficial for
对你的 Swift 代码
your SWF code because data races
非常有益 因为数据竞争
and access races are undefined
和访问竞争是 Swift 中的未定义行为
behavior in SWF and they could
并且可能
lead to memory corruptions.
导致内存损坏
For more information about this
有关此工具的更多信息
tool, watch the Finding Bugs
请观看“使用 Xcode 运行时工具查找 Bug”
Using Xcode Runtime Tools talk.
的演讲
Now, safety is a design choice
总之 安全是 Swift 的一个设计
in SWF.
选择
The language provides many
该语言提供了许多
solutions to avoid undefined
解决方案来避免未定义行为
behavior and prevent developers
并阻止开发人员
from introducing subtle and
引入微妙和
exploitable bugs.
可利用的 Bug
Today we talked about undefined
今天我们讨论了未定义行为
behavior and how different
以及不同的语言如何
languages approach it.
解决这个问题
C languages use undefined
C 语言使用未定义行为
behavior for portability and
进行轻量化和
optimizations.
优化
However, we've seen that that
然而 我们已经看到了
could lead to very subtle and
这可能会导致非常微妙和
hard to debug bugs and even
难以调试的 Bug  甚至会
introduce security exploits.
引入安全漏洞
SWF chose to follow a different
Swift 选择遵循不同的
path and was designed to be
路径 并且被设计成
safer by default.
在默认情况下更安全
Finally, regardless of your
最后 无论你
language of choice, use all the
选择哪种语言 请使用所有
tools at your disposal as part
可用的工具作为
of your app release and testing
应用程序发布和测试过程的
process.
一部分
That will make your apps more
这将使你的应用程序更加
secure and robust.
安全可靠
Here are some of the related
这里是我们
sessions that we've mentioned
今天提到的一些
today.
相关会议
Thank you very much and enjoy
非常感谢 祝你
the rest of your day.
愉快地度过今天接下来的时间
[ Applause ]
[掌声]